<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<channel>
		<title>TrueCraft Blog</title>
		<description>Updates from the TrueCraft team</description>
        <link>http://truecraft.io/</link>
        <atom:link href="http://truecraft.io/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		
			<item>
				<title>Performance &amp; stability improvements</title>
                <description>
                    <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://sr.ht/2V_g.png" />
                    <p>Spent the past couple of days working on server performance and stability improvements. In
particular, common deadlocks have been fixed, chunk loading performance has been
improved, and many tasks were adjusted to more intelligently use the thread pool and divide
work between the main thread and thread pool (without breaking things).</p>
<p>Also fixed a number of small bugs like deterministic terrain generation issues and dungeon
generation, and added some new features for tweaking what processes are running in the
server (allowing you to, for example, disable fire spread or grass growth). Some of the major
issues with the physics engine and mob pathfinding were sorted out yesterday.</p>
<p>I have some more performance issues to work through and bugs to sort out tomorrow. In the
coming days and weeks, I hope to square away most of the important bugs in the server, and
start on improving mob AI, combat, and more interesting stuff. A rewrite of the client rendering
stack is also in the cards.</p>
<p>Big thanks to Aaron on <a href="https://patreon.com/sircmpwn">Patreon</a>, who's pledged $50/month
asking for more work on TrueCraft. No problem, Aaron! Thanks!</p>
                    ]]>
                </description>
				<pubDate>Wed, 24 May 2017 01:21:24 </pubDate>
                <link>http://truecraft.io/blog/40/Performance%20%26%20stability%20improvements</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://truecraft.io/blog/40/Performance%20%26%20stability%20improvements</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Patreon</title>
                <description>
                    <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://sr.ht/f4X6.png" />
                    <p>I've made a Patreon page to support my free software projects, including TrueCraft.</p>
<p>If it seems like TrueCraft development has stalled lately, it's because that's exactly what's
happened. Unfortunately, I don't have time to support TrueCraft while trying to make a living.
If you're disappointed by the inactivity and you want to see a change, I encourage you to
contribute on the Patreon page and let me know that you'd like to see your contributions go
towards TrueCraft.</p>
<p>https://patreon.com/sircmpwn</p>
<p>Many thanks!</p>
                    ]]>
                </description>
				<pubDate>Thu, 11 May 2017 15:59:31 </pubDate>
                <link>http://truecraft.io/blog/39/Patreon</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://truecraft.io/blog/39/Patreon</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Improvements to physics engine</title>
                <description>
                    <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://sr.ht/RniF.png" />
                    <p>Today I hopped back into TrueCraft dev for a little while to deal with some issues concerning
the physics engine. There were some cases where you could walk into corners and end up not
triggering a collision, which would lead to the player being flung high up into the air once they
were detected to be inside of a block on the next tick.</p>
<p>Another issue I resolved was the problem of placing blocks where entities already exist. I just
did some tweaks to the existing code that did not work to make it do the correct thing (i.e.
prevent you from placing a block that would collide with an entity that's already there).</p>
<p>I have some issues to figure out with entity collisions in practice on the server, where they
still behave very strangely. The physics improvements I put in place today seem to help with
player movement but items and other entities are still FUBAR.</p>
                    ]]>
                </description>
				<pubDate>Tue, 05 Jul 2016 00:38:43 </pubDate>
                <link>http://truecraft.io/blog/38/Improvements%20to%20physics%20engine</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://truecraft.io/blog/38/Improvements%20to%20physics%20engine</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Rendering the day/night cycle lighting in the client</title>
                <description>
                    <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://sr.ht/A7lE.png" />
                    <p>I didn't plan on working on TrueCraft today, but I got on Twitch.tv to stream and one thing led to
another. I have implemented the day/night cycle in the client, though it's still a little bit buggy. The
sun and moon textures now included by default with TrueCraft are courtesey of the
<a href="http://www.minecrafttexturepacks.com/isabella/">Isabella pack</a>, which is CC-BY-SA, since our
current texture pack didn't actually override the sun/moon textures from Minecraft.</p>
<p>If you're curious what the daytime looks like, the answer is probably "weird" because of an issue
with the calculation of the sky color. But at sunset it looks quite nice:</p>
<p><img alt="" src="https://sr.ht/915K.png" /></p>
<p>Next time I plan on working on the physics engine and improving the stability of the server. The
former will lead to better support (or any support, really) for mobs.</p>
                    ]]>
                </description>
				<pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2016 00:59:31 </pubDate>
                <link>http://truecraft.io/blog/37/Rendering%20the%20day/night%20cycle%20lighting%20in%20the%20client</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://truecraft.io/blog/37/Rendering%20the%20day/night%20cycle%20lighting%20in%20the%20client</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Improvements to client side lighting and performance</title>
                <description>
                    <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://sr.ht/NWwz.png" />
                    <p>Today I spent some time on Twitch streaming some TrueCraft work, and I finished up the lighting
improvements started by mrpimpunicorn in the client. I fixed a few issues with things like snow,
which you may have noticed had horribly broken lighting, and I fixed issues with the blocks that
were lit incorrectly at chunk boundaries.</p>
<p>I also implemented updating the lighting when the client mines a block, as well as re-rendering
chunks when adjacent chunks show up, which can be a big improvement for performance since
we can eliminate a lot of verticies once we know what the adjacent chunk looks like.</p>
<p>Up next I plan on fixing up the mobs and perhaps even implementing mob rendering in the client.</p>
<p>As a parting thought, here's another screenshot of what the lighting for snow <em>used</em> to look like:</p>
<p><img alt="" src="https://sr.ht/9mMf.png" /></p>
                    ]]>
                </description>
				<pubDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2016 01:44:55 </pubDate>
                <link>http://truecraft.io/blog/36/Improvements%20to%20client%20side%20lighting%20and%20performance</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://truecraft.io/blog/36/Improvements%20to%20client%20side%20lighting%20and%20performance</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Multiplatform update - call for contributors</title>
                <description>
                    <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://sr.ht/u49E.png" />
                    <p>Thanks to some improvements from MonoGame 3.5, I was able to drop some platform-specific
hacks from the TrueCraft client, which means it works for most Windows users now. I also
spent some time trying to get it working on OSX - and I did, but only as a proof of concept. I
encourage readers who are comfortable writing software for OSX to hop in and help build a more
mature port. Join us <a href="http://webchat.esper.net/?nick=&amp;channels=truecraft">on IRC</a> if you're
interested.</p>
<p>I still don't use Windows, so I would also still appreciate contributors from Windowsland keeping
that port in good shape. Hop into IRC if you can help with this, too.</p>
<p>The Linux port has also been updated to use GTK3 if available for the Launcher, and now
includes Wayland support.</p>
                    ]]>
                </description>
				<pubDate>Sat, 19 Mar 2016 12:56:51 </pubDate>
                <link>http://truecraft.io/blog/35/Multiplatform%20update%20-%20call%20for%20contributors</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://truecraft.io/blog/35/Multiplatform%20update%20-%20call%20for%20contributors</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Inventory windows on the client</title>
                <description>
                    <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://sr.ht/d9ua.jpg https://sr.ht/XDj1.webm" />
                    <p>I have (mostly) implemented windows on the client! Since crafting and window management is
already handled on the server, we automatically get crafting support on the client with this. That
means that the TrueCraft client is actually pretty playable as a result!</p>
<p>Windows other than your inventory window are not going to work, though. I still have to add the
crafting bench, furnace, and chest windows (and eventually dispensers, though the server does
not currently support that).</p>
                    ]]>
                </description>
				<pubDate>Fri, 09 Oct 2015 01:50:38 </pubDate>
                <link>http://truecraft.io/blog/34/Inventory%20windows%20on%20the%20client</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://truecraft.io/blog/34/Inventory%20windows%20on%20the%20client</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Smelting on the server, audio on the client</title>
                <description>
                    <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://sr.ht/OGQM.png" />
                    <p>I finally put in the effort for making smelting work on TrueCraft servers. As a result, it's now
possible to obtain a much larger variety of items in a TrueCraft game, though some of them
remain unobtainable due to the limitations of terrain generation.</p>
<p>Additionally, I have started to add sound effects to the TrueCraft client. Thanks to the Minetest
project for offering up the relevant sounds under CC-BY-SA! I'm also in touch with a guy who
wants to help compose original music for TrueCraft, also CC-BY-SA. The sound effects are
currently limited to making noise as you walk, but is smart enough to play different effects based
on what you're walking on. I will soon add sound effects for mining and placing blocks, among
other things.</p>
<p>I'll leave you with another screenshot, this time of my test runway for sound effects:</p>
<p><img alt="" src="https://sr.ht/dliI.png" /></p>
                    ]]>
                </description>
				<pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2015 02:13:54 </pubDate>
                <link>http://truecraft.io/blog/33/Smelting%20on%20the%20server%2C%20audio%20on%20the%20client</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://truecraft.io/blog/33/Smelting%20on%20the%20server%2C%20audio%20on%20the%20client</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>New texture pack, gamepad support</title>
                <description>
                    <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://sr.ht/aKPe.png" />
                    <p>I spent some time this morning adding gamepad support to TrueCraft (a feature that even the
newest versions of Minecraft still don't have!). It's currently geared towards Xbox 360 controllers,
but will probably work with whatever you've got. I will eventually add support for rebinding your
gamepad actions when I work on rebinding keyboard actions.</p>
<p>I also reached out to <a href="https://twitter.com/Mruqe">Wojtek Mroczek</a>, the author of the old Pixeludi
texture pack for Minecraft. I think this texture pack stays
pretty close to the feel of Minecraft, while still being entirely original (and much better than my
crappy attempts at artwork). He agreed to let me distribute his textures under CC-BY-SA, and I
am happy to adopt them as the default texture pack for TrueCraft. Of course, you can still install
any other texture pack you like.</p>
<p>Next batch of changes will just be improvements to the existing stuff. After that, I'm planning on
leaving the client behind for a bit and doing some improvements to the server like smelting and
mob optimizations (and spawning by default, if I get the optimizations right).</p>
                    ]]>
                </description>
				<pubDate>Fri, 02 Oct 2015 02:49:55 </pubDate>
                <link>http://truecraft.io/blog/32/New%20texture%20pack%2C%20gamepad%20support</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://truecraft.io/blog/32/New%20texture%20pack%2C%20gamepad%20support</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Now you can place blocks on the client!</title>
                <description>
                    <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://sr.ht/gDH6.jpg https://sr.ht/7itO.webm" />
                    <p>After implementing mining yesterday, I implemented the reverse today. Now you can place
blocks! This is actually more than just placing blocks, though - it sends an "interact" message to
the server, which is basically any action that's done with a right click. So now you can place
blocks, plant crops, open doors, and so on.</p>
<p>The new hotbar appearance also supports texture packs. Here's what it looks like with some
others:</p>
<p><img alt="" src="https://sr.ht/SavH.png" /></p>
<p><img alt="" src="https://sr.ht/FLHt.png" /></p>
<p><img alt="" src="https://sr.ht/KtGv.png" /></p>
<p>mrpimpunicorn helped out with rendering the hotbar today.</p>
<p>The TrueCraft item sprites haven't been worked on, so they don't look very good. But we'll work
on them! Or if you're the artsy type and you'd like to help out, how about offering up some
improvements yourself? <a href="https://github.com/SirCmpwn/TrueCraft">Visit our Github</a> or our
<a href="http://webchat.esper.net/?nick=&amp;channels=truecraft">chat room</a> if you're interested.</p>
                    ]]>
                </description>
				<pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2015 00:34:28 </pubDate>
                <link>http://truecraft.io/blog/31/Now%20you%20can%20place%20blocks%20on%20the%20client%21</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://truecraft.io/blog/31/Now%20you%20can%20place%20blocks%20on%20the%20client%21</guid>
			</item>
		
	</channel>
</rss>